<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>steps on Hyperfoil</title><link>https://lampajr.github.io/hyperfoil-website-demo/tags/steps/</link><description>Recent content in steps on Hyperfoil</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><atom:link href="https://lampajr.github.io/hyperfoil-website-demo/tags/steps/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Steps</title><link>https://lampajr.github.io/hyperfoil-website-demo/docs/reference/steps/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://lampajr.github.io/hyperfoil-website-demo/docs/reference/steps/</guid><description>Steps are the basic building blocks that form each sequence of a scenario, similar to statements in a programming language. Steps are potentially blocking (the sequence cannot continue with next step until previous one finishes).
Note that every action can be also used as a step that simply never blocks, as actions do not require any extra input.</description></item><item><title>Steps and statistics</title><link>https://lampajr.github.io/hyperfoil-website-demo/docs/getting-started/quickstart2/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://lampajr.github.io/hyperfoil-website-demo/docs/getting-started/quickstart2/</guid><description>In previous quickstart you created a benchmark that fires only one HTTP request. Our next example is going to hit random URLs at this server with 10 requests per second. We&amp;rsquo;ll see how to generate random data and collect statistics for different URLs.
Let&amp;rsquo;s start a container that will serve the requests:
podman run --rm -p 8080:8083 quay.io/hyperfoil/hyperfoil-examples If you prefer running this in Docker just replace podman with docker. You can explore the handling of requests from this example on GitHub.</description></item><item><title>Custom components</title><link>https://lampajr.github.io/hyperfoil-website-demo/docs/getting-started/quickstart8/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://lampajr.github.io/hyperfoil-website-demo/docs/getting-started/quickstart8/</guid><description>Hyperfoil offers some basic steps to do HTTP requests, generate data, alter control flow in the scenario etc., but your needs may surpass the features implemented so far. Also, it might be just easier to express your logic in Java code than combining steps in the YAML. The downside is reduced ability to reuse and more tight dependency on Hyperfoil APIs.
This quickstart will show you how to extend Hyperfoil with custom steps and handlers.</description></item></channel></rss>