<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Installation on Hyperfoil</title><link>https://lampajr.github.io/hyperfoil-website-demo/categories/installation/</link><description>Recent content in Installation on Hyperfoil</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><atom:link href="https://lampajr.github.io/hyperfoil-website-demo/categories/installation/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Installation</title><link>https://lampajr.github.io/hyperfoil-website-demo/docs/user-guide/installation/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://lampajr.github.io/hyperfoil-website-demo/docs/user-guide/installation/</guid><description>In this section, you’ll find detailed instructions for installing and setting up Hyperfoil using various methods, including manual setup, Ansible, and Kubernetes/Openshift. Follow these guides to choose the best installation procedure for your environment.</description></item><item><title>Manual startup</title><link>https://lampajr.github.io/hyperfoil-website-demo/docs/user-guide/installation/start_manual/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://lampajr.github.io/hyperfoil-website-demo/docs/user-guide/installation/start_manual/</guid><description>Hyperfoil controller is started with
bin/controller.sh Any arguments passed to the scripts will be passed as-is to the java process.
By default io.hyperfoil.deployer is set to ssh which means that the controller will deploy agents over SSH, based on the agents configurion. This requires that the user account running the controller must have public-key SSH authorization set up using key $HOME/.ssh/id_rsa. The user also has to be able to copy files to the directory set in agent definition (by default /tmp/hyperfoil) using SCP - Hyperfoil automatically synchronizes library files in this folder with the currently running instance and then executes the agent.</description></item><item><title>K8s/Openshift deployment</title><link>https://lampajr.github.io/hyperfoil-website-demo/docs/user-guide/installation/k8s/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://lampajr.github.io/hyperfoil-website-demo/docs/user-guide/installation/k8s/</guid><description>A convenient alternative to running Hyperfoil on hosts with SSH access is deploying it in Kubernetes or Openshift environment. The recommended way to install it using an operator in your Openshift console - just go to Operators - OperatorHub and search for &amp;lsquo;hyperfoil&amp;rsquo;, and follow the installation wizard. Alternatively you can deploy the controller manually.
In order to start a Hyperfoil Controller instance in your cluster, create a new namespace hyperfoil: Go to Operators - Installed Operators and open Hyperfoil.</description></item><item><title>Manual k8s/Openshift deployment</title><link>https://lampajr.github.io/hyperfoil-website-demo/docs/user-guide/installation/k8s_manual/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://lampajr.github.io/hyperfoil-website-demo/docs/user-guide/installation/k8s_manual/</guid><description>If you cannot use the operator or if you&amp;rsquo;re running vanilla Kubernetes you can define all the resource manually. You deploy only the controller; each agent is then started, when the run starts, as a pod in the same namespace and stopped when the run completes.
Following steps install Hyperfoil controller in Openshift, assuming that you have all the required priviledges. With vanilla Kubernetes you might have to replace the route with an appropriate ingress.</description></item><item><title>Ansible startup</title><link>https://lampajr.github.io/hyperfoil-website-demo/docs/user-guide/installation/ansible/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://lampajr.github.io/hyperfoil-website-demo/docs/user-guide/installation/ansible/</guid><description>You can fetch release, distribute and start the cluster using Ansible Galaxy scripts; setup, test, shutdown
First, get the scripts:
ansible-galaxy install hyperfoil.hyperfoil_setup,{{ site.last_release.galaxy_version }} ansible-galaxy install hyperfoil.hyperfoil_shutdown,{{ site.last_release.galaxy_version }} ansible-galaxy install hyperfoil.hyperfoil_test,{{ site.last_release.galaxy_version }} Now, edit your hosts file, it could look like this:
[hyperfoil-controller] controller ansible_host=localhost [hyperfoil-agent] agent-1 ansible_host=localhost Note You can add more agents by duplicating the last line with agent-2 etc. Prepare your playbook; here is a short example that starts the controller, uploads and starts simple benchmark (the templating engine replaces the agents in benchmark script based on Ansible hosts) and waits for its completion.</description></item></channel></rss>