<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Actions on Hyperfoil</title><link>https://lampajr.github.io/hyperfoil-website-demo/docs/reference/actions/</link><description>Recent content in Actions on Hyperfoil</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><atom:link href="https://lampajr.github.io/hyperfoil-website-demo/docs/reference/actions/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>addItem</title><link>https://lampajr.github.io/hyperfoil-website-demo/docs/reference/actions/action_additem/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://lampajr.github.io/hyperfoil-website-demo/docs/reference/actions/action_additem/</guid><description>Appends value to an array stored in another variable.
Property Type Description fromVar String Fetch value from session variable. toVar String Destination variable with the array. value String Verbatim value.</description></item><item><title>addToInt</title><link>https://lampajr.github.io/hyperfoil-website-demo/docs/reference/actions/action_addtoint/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://lampajr.github.io/hyperfoil-website-demo/docs/reference/actions/action_addtoint/</guid><description>Add value to integer variable in the session.
Inline definition Accepting one of: var++, var&amp;ndash;, var += value, var -= value. Property Type Description orElseSetTo int If the variable is currently not set, set it to this value instead of addition. value int Value added (can be negative). var String Variable name.</description></item><item><title>addToSharedCounter</title><link>https://lampajr.github.io/hyperfoil-website-demo/docs/reference/actions/action_addtosharedcounter/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://lampajr.github.io/hyperfoil-website-demo/docs/reference/actions/action_addtosharedcounter/</guid><description>Adds value to a counter shared by all sessions in the same executor.
Inline definition Use on of: counter++, counter&amp;ndash;, counter += &amp;lt;value&amp;gt;, counter -= &amp;lt;value&amp;gt; Property Type Description fromVar String Input variable name. key String Identifier for the counter. operator enum Operation to perform on the counter. Default is ADD.
Options:ADDSUBTRACT value int Value (integer).</description></item><item><title>clearHttpCache</title><link>https://lampajr.github.io/hyperfoil-website-demo/docs/reference/actions/action_clearhttpcache/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://lampajr.github.io/hyperfoil-website-demo/docs/reference/actions/action_clearhttpcache/</guid><description>Drops all entries from HTTP cache in the session.</description></item><item><title>conditional</title><link>https://lampajr.github.io/hyperfoil-website-demo/docs/reference/actions/action_conditional/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://lampajr.github.io/hyperfoil-website-demo/docs/reference/actions/action_conditional/</guid><description>Perform an action or sequence of actions conditionally.
Property Type Description actions Action.Builder Actions that should be executed should the condition hold. allConditions Builder Condition combining multiple other conditions with &amp;lsquo;AND&amp;rsquo; logic. boolCondition Builder Condition comparing boolean variables. intCondition Builder Condition comparing integer variables. stringCondition Builder Condition comparing string variables. allConditions Test more conditions and combine the results using AND logic.
Property Type Description &amp;lt;list of mappings&amp;gt; &amp;lt;list of builders&amp;gt; List of conditions.</description></item><item><title>fail</title><link>https://lampajr.github.io/hyperfoil-website-demo/docs/reference/actions/action_fail/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://lampajr.github.io/hyperfoil-website-demo/docs/reference/actions/action_fail/</guid><description>Fail the phase with given message. Used mostly for testing/debugging.
Inline definition Message to fail with (unconditionally). Property Type Description allConditions Builder Condition combining multiple other conditions with &amp;lsquo;AND&amp;rsquo; logic. boolCondition Builder Condition comparing boolean variables. intCondition Builder Condition comparing integer variables. message String Message attached to the failure exception. stringCondition Builder Condition comparing string variables. allConditions Test more conditions and combine the results using AND logic.
Property Type Description &amp;lt;list of mappings&amp;gt; &amp;lt;list of builders&amp;gt; List of conditions.</description></item><item><title>getIndex</title><link>https://lampajr.github.io/hyperfoil-website-demo/docs/reference/actions/action_getindex/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://lampajr.github.io/hyperfoil-website-demo/docs/reference/actions/action_getindex/</guid><description>Lookup index of an item in an array/collection.
Property Type Description collection String Variable to fetch the collection from. item Builder Item that should be looked up (using equality). toVar String Integer variable to store the index, or -1 if the item is not found. item Inline definition Verbatim value. Property Type Description fromVar String Fetch value from session variable. value String Verbatim value.</description></item><item><title>getItem</title><link>https://lampajr.github.io/hyperfoil-website-demo/docs/reference/actions/action_getitem/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://lampajr.github.io/hyperfoil-website-demo/docs/reference/actions/action_getitem/</guid><description>Retrieves n-th item from an array or collection.
Property Type Description fromVar String Source variable with an array or list. index Builder Source for index into the array/list. toVar String Destination variable for the n-th element. index Inline definition Uses the argument as a constant value. Property Type Description fromVar String Input variable name. value int Value (integer).</description></item><item><title>getSharedCounter</title><link>https://lampajr.github.io/hyperfoil-website-demo/docs/reference/actions/action_getsharedcounter/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://lampajr.github.io/hyperfoil-website-demo/docs/reference/actions/action_getsharedcounter/</guid><description>Retrieves value from a counter shared by all sessions in the same executor and stores that in a session variable. If the value exceeds allowed integer range (-2^31 .. 2^31 - 1) it is capped.
Inline definition Both the key and variable name. Property Type Description key String Identifier for the counter. toVar String Session variable for storing the value.</description></item><item><title>getSize</title><link>https://lampajr.github.io/hyperfoil-website-demo/docs/reference/actions/action_getsize/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://lampajr.github.io/hyperfoil-website-demo/docs/reference/actions/action_getsize/</guid><description>Calculates size of an array/collection held in variable into another variable
Property Type Description boolFilter Builder Count only items matching the condition. fromVar String Variable holding the collection. intFilter Builder Count only items matching the condition. stringFilter Builder Count only items matching the condition. toVar String Variable storing the size. undefinedValue int Value to use when fromVar is unset or it does not contain any array/collection. boolFilter Property Type Description value boolean Expected value.</description></item><item><title>log</title><link>https://lampajr.github.io/hyperfoil-website-demo/docs/reference/actions/action_log/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://lampajr.github.io/hyperfoil-website-demo/docs/reference/actions/action_log/</guid><description>Log a message and variable values.
Inline definition A pattern for string interpolation. Property Type Description message String Message format pattern. Use string interpolation for variables.</description></item><item><title>markRequestInvalid</title><link>https://lampajr.github.io/hyperfoil-website-demo/docs/reference/actions/action_markrequestinvalid/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://lampajr.github.io/hyperfoil-website-demo/docs/reference/actions/action_markrequestinvalid/</guid><description>Unconditionally mark currently processed request as invalid.</description></item><item><title>newSequence</title><link>https://lampajr.github.io/hyperfoil-website-demo/docs/reference/actions/action_newsequence/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://lampajr.github.io/hyperfoil-website-demo/docs/reference/actions/action_newsequence/</guid><description>Instantiates a sequence for each invocation.
Inline definition Sequence name. Property Type Description concurrencyPolicy enum Options:FAILWARN forceSameIndex boolean Forces that the sequence will have the same index as the currently executing sequence. This can be useful if the sequence is passing some data to the new sequence using sequence-scoped variables. Note that the new sequence must have same concurrency factor as the currently executing sequence. sequence String Name of the instantiated sequence.</description></item><item><title>publishAgentData</title><link>https://lampajr.github.io/hyperfoil-website-demo/docs/reference/actions/action_publishagentdata/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://lampajr.github.io/hyperfoil-website-demo/docs/reference/actions/action_publishagentdata/</guid><description>Makes the data available to all sessions in the same agent, including those using different executors.
Inline definition Both name of source variable and the key used to read the data. Property Type Description fromVar String Source session variable name. name String Arbitrary unique identifier for the data.</description></item><item><title>publishGlobalCounters</title><link>https://lampajr.github.io/hyperfoil-website-demo/docs/reference/actions/action_publishglobalcounters/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://lampajr.github.io/hyperfoil-website-demo/docs/reference/actions/action_publishglobalcounters/</guid><description>Gathers values from session variables and publishes them globally (to all agents). You can name the counters individually (example 1) or use the variable names (example 2): # Example 1: - publishGlobalCounters: key: myKey vars: [ foo, bar ] # Example 2: - publishGlobalCounters: key: someOtherKey vars: - foo: myFoo - bar: bbb &amp;lt;/code&amp;gt;``` | Property | Type | Description | | ------- | ------- | -------- | | key | String | Identifier of the global record.</description></item><item><title>readAgentData</title><link>https://lampajr.github.io/hyperfoil-website-demo/docs/reference/actions/action_readagentdata/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://lampajr.github.io/hyperfoil-website-demo/docs/reference/actions/action_readagentdata/</guid><description>Reads data from agent-wide scope into session variable.
The data must be published in a phase that has terminated before this phase starts: usually this is achieved using the startAfterStrict property on the phase.
Inline definition Both the identifier and destination session variable. Property Type Description name String Unique identifier for the data. toVar String Destination session variable name.</description></item><item><title>removeItem</title><link>https://lampajr.github.io/hyperfoil-website-demo/docs/reference/actions/action_removeitem/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://lampajr.github.io/hyperfoil-website-demo/docs/reference/actions/action_removeitem/</guid><description>Removes element from an array of variables.
Property Type Description fromVar String Variable containing an existing array of object variables. index Builder Set index at which the item should be removed. Elements to the right of this are moved to the left. index Inline definition Uses the argument as a constant value. Property Type Description fromVar String Input variable name. value int Value (integer).</description></item><item><title>restartSequence</title><link>https://lampajr.github.io/hyperfoil-website-demo/docs/reference/actions/action_restartsequence/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://lampajr.github.io/hyperfoil-website-demo/docs/reference/actions/action_restartsequence/</guid><description>Schedules a restart of this sequence.</description></item><item><title>set</title><link>https://lampajr.github.io/hyperfoil-website-demo/docs/reference/actions/action_set/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://lampajr.github.io/hyperfoil-website-demo/docs/reference/actions/action_set/</guid><description>Set variable in session to certain value.
Inline definition Use var &amp;lt;- value. Property Type Description intArray Builder Set variable to an (unset) integer array. objectArray Builder Set variable to an (unset) object array. value String String value. var String Variable name. intArray Creates integer arrays to be stored in the session.
Property Type Description fromVar String Contents of the new array. If the variable contains an array or a list, items will be copied to the elements with the same index up to the size of this array.</description></item><item><title>setInt</title><link>https://lampajr.github.io/hyperfoil-website-demo/docs/reference/actions/action_setint/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://lampajr.github.io/hyperfoil-website-demo/docs/reference/actions/action_setint/</guid><description>Set session variable to an integral value.
Inline definition Use var &amp;lt;- value. Property Type Description fromVar String Input variable name. intCondition Builder Set variable only if the current value satisfies certain condition. max Builder Set to value that is the maximum of this list of values. min Builder Set to value that is the minimum of this list of values. onlyIfNotSet boolean Set variable to the value only if it is not already set.</description></item><item><title>setItem</title><link>https://lampajr.github.io/hyperfoil-website-demo/docs/reference/actions/action_setitem/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://lampajr.github.io/hyperfoil-website-demo/docs/reference/actions/action_setitem/</guid><description>Set element in a collection on given position.
Property Type Description fromVar String Fetch value from session variable. index Builder Integer session variable with an index into the collection. toVar String Session variable with the collection. value String Verbatim value. index Inline definition Uses the argument as a constant value. Property Type Description fromVar String Input variable name. value int Value (integer).</description></item><item><title>setSharedCounter</title><link>https://lampajr.github.io/hyperfoil-website-demo/docs/reference/actions/action_setsharedcounter/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://lampajr.github.io/hyperfoil-website-demo/docs/reference/actions/action_setsharedcounter/</guid><description>Sets value in a counter shared by all sessions in the same executor.
Inline definition Both the name of the counter and variable name. Property Type Description fromVar String Input variable name. key String Identifier for the counter. value int Value (integer).</description></item><item><title>stringToInt</title><link>https://lampajr.github.io/hyperfoil-website-demo/docs/reference/actions/action_stringtoint/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://lampajr.github.io/hyperfoil-website-demo/docs/reference/actions/action_stringtoint/</guid><description>Parse string into integer and store it in a variable.
If the parsing fails the target variable is not modified.
Inline definition Use fromVar -&amp;amp;gt; toVar Property Type Description fromVar String Source variable name. toVar String Target variable name.</description></item><item><title>unset</title><link>https://lampajr.github.io/hyperfoil-website-demo/docs/reference/actions/action_unset/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://lampajr.github.io/hyperfoil-website-demo/docs/reference/actions/action_unset/</guid><description>Undefine variable name.
Inline definition Variable name. Property Type Description var Object Variable name.</description></item></channel></rss>