<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>phases on Hyperfoil</title><link>https://lampajr.github.io/hyperfoil-website-demo/tags/phases/</link><description>Recent content in phases on Hyperfoil</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><atom:link href="https://lampajr.github.io/hyperfoil-website-demo/tags/phases/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Phases</title><link>https://lampajr.github.io/hyperfoil-website-demo/docs/user-guide/benchmark/phases/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://lampajr.github.io/hyperfoil-website-demo/docs/user-guide/benchmark/phases/</guid><description>You might want to simulate several types of workloads at once: e.g. in an eshop users would come browsing or buying products, and operators would restock the virtual warehouse. Also, driving constant load may not be the best way to run the benchmark: often you want to slowly ramp the load up to let the system adjust (scale up, perform JIT, fill pools) and push the full load only after that.</description></item><item><title>Phases - basics</title><link>https://lampajr.github.io/hyperfoil-website-demo/docs/getting-started/quickstart4/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://lampajr.github.io/hyperfoil-website-demo/docs/getting-started/quickstart4/</guid><description>So far the benchmark contained only one type of load; certain number of users hitting the system, doing always the same (though data could be randomized). In practice you might want to simulate several types of workloads at once: in an eshop users would come browsing or buying products, and operators would restock the virtual warehouse.
Also, driving constant load may not be the best way to run the benchmark: often you want to slowly ramp the load up to let the system adjust (scale up, perform JIT, fill pools) and push the full load only after that.</description></item><item><title>Phases - advanced</title><link>https://lampajr.github.io/hyperfoil-website-demo/docs/getting-started/quickstart5/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://lampajr.github.io/hyperfoil-website-demo/docs/getting-started/quickstart5/</guid><description>Previous quickstart presented a benchmark with three phases that all started at the same moment (when the benchmark was started) and had the same duration - different phases represented different workflows (types of user). In this example we will adjust the benchmark to scale the load gradually up.
At this point it would be useful to mention the lifecycle of phases; phase is in one of these states:
not started: As the name clearly says, the phase is not yet started.</description></item></channel></rss>